David Watson david@davidwatson.org

Summary

I help teams design, develop, and deploy software. I'm comfortable working alone, in pairs, or groups establishing consensus among competing constraints.

My work has spanned desktop to data center and mobile to cloud in a variety of business domains from startups to small research labs.

I've worked primarily in C++ and Python on Linux, Mac, and Windows.

Using a variety of tools such as Docker, Kubernetes, and PostgreSQL provides teams with a common foundation for building software.

When I'm not working, I like to bike, run, and ski. I relax by reading, writing, and reflecting.

Experience

Software Engineering Specialist Caterpillar 2018-2020, 2021

- Contributed code and review to multiple projects within autonomy group
- Consulted with several groups on their use of docker containers and CI/CD

Member of Technical Staff Carnegie Mellon University 2020

- Contributed to Emerging Technology Center within Software Engineering Institute
- · Work included High Performance Computing, data engineering, and Human Computer Interaction

Senior Software Developer Realpage 2016 - 2018

- Contributed code and process to software engineering team
- Implemented crawler data pipeline using Python, PostgreSQL, Docker, and Kubernetes

VP Product Development Wellbridge Health 2015 - 2016

- Led development team through replacement of legacy prototype with new product
- Designed and implemented REST API using DRF and PostgreSQL on web and mobile

VP Engineering Hire an Esquire 2014

- Led engineering team from rough prototype to mature product
- Refactored Python, Django, and PostgreSQL stack

Senior Software Developer Forever 2013 - 2014

- Contributed code from prototype to product
- Wrote Python, Flask, MongoDB prototype, productionized Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

Senior Engineer Smash 2011 - 2012

- Contributed code to internal systems supporting daily operations
- Designed and implemented conversational text systems and REST interfaces in python

Software Development Manager Wellspring 2010 - 2011

- Led development team from legacy data center to SaaS virtualization
- Prototyped DevOps (CI/CD) approach using Capistrano, Mechanize, and Selenium

Project Engineer Applied Perception 2008-2009

- Contributed code to teams working on military robotics projects (DARPA)
- Visualized XML sonar data in python, ported Microsoft C#.net Windows GUI to C++/Qt/Linux

UI Software Engineer Nomos 2006 - 2007

- Contributed code, tests, and review to several radiation oncology software products
- Prototyped wireframes and storyboards in C++/Qt for adaptive 4D treatment planning

Software Design Engineer MAYA Design 2004 - 2006

- Contributed design, analysis, and code across numerous consulting projects
- Coded AJAX backends in python and a wireless lighting system in C# for Philips

Co-Founder Cobind 2003 - 2004

- Partnered on ideation, vision, and execution of custom Linux Tools startup
- Received wide press acclaim around custom Linux products after winning Idea Foundry Fellowship

Senior Software Engineer MSA 2000-2003

- Contributed code, data, and deployment before and after startup acquisition
- Implemented product import systems providing Excel VBA API from spreadsheet to database

Member of Technical Staff CA 1995-2000

- Contributed code to Automation Point, Raveler, and CA-Unicenter products
- Coded C++ GUI code for Legent and Platinum, before and after CA acquisition

Programmer-Analyst Mellon 1992-1995

- Contributed code to Executive Workbench asset management product
- Implemented multi-threaded, event-driven C++ GUI code on OS/2

Programmer-Analyst USX 1990-1992

- Contributed code to internal data center systems automation
- Automated data center operations in C/HLLAPI on OS/2 from a networked PC

Sites

- GitHub
- LinkedIn

Education

• Bachelor of Science, Duquesne University 1991